Miguel Ángel García

Web: http://miguel.ga

Location: Argentina, Capital Federal

LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/zzmike
GitHub: https://github.com/miguelgarcia



Profile

I'm a Licentiate in Computer Science from University of Buenos Aires, graduated on 2016. I've been interested in computers and technology since I was a kid and I've been working as a software developer and IT consultant since 2004.

I like building things using open source technologies and working on projects that allow me to learn. I consider myself a fast learner and have no problem learning new languages or technologies.

When between professional projects I like to solve algorithms problems to keep myself trained.

I'm based in Buenos Aires, Argentina and prefer to work remotely.

Education

Licentiate in Computer Science (equivalent to Master degree in USA: 6 years plus thesis) graduated on 2016 at "Faculty of Exact and Natural Sciences, University of Buenos Aires". GPA: 8.5/10

Licentiate thesis: "Techniques and methodologies for vision systems implementation on All Programmable SoCs using High Level Synthesis" (https://github.com/miguelgarcia/tesis-apsoc)

The thesis received these awards:

- •1st award at the JAIIO45 "Students Thesis Contest"
- •1st mention by CESSI (Argentina Software industry companies organizations) at the JAIIO45

Courses Taken

- Learning GO LinkedIn Learning
- SCRUM: The Basics LinkedIn Learning
- Learn DevOPs: The complete Kubernetes Course UDEMY

Professional Experience

ENACOM (Ente Nacional de Comunicaciones, Argentina government): IT Consultant 2017-now

Design and implementation of a web platform to ease the reception and processing of information from telecommunication providers using Python, PostgreSQL, AMQP, Docker and Bonita BPMs.

Freelancer Software Developer / Consultant

2017-now

Development of web applications for medium sized companies and organizations using Python, React, SQL and NoSQL databases.

Enjambre Bit SRL: Co-founder / Full stack developer

2015-2017

Enjambre Bit is a custom software development firm founded by me and three colleagues on 2015. I departed Enjambre on 2017 to focus on other projects.

Applications development for various customers using Ember JS, Electron, Python and Docker. The most important project was http://pilasbloques.program.ar/ a platform to help kids learn computer programming using blocks.

ANSES Conectar Igualdad, Huayra Linux: Linux developer

2012-2015

Conectar Igualdad was an Argentina government program to supply each high school student with a laptop computer. Huayra GNU/Linux is a Debian based Linux distro built for Conectar Igualdad laptops.

During my time at the Huayra team I did multiple tasks, like:

- Desktop applications development with QT and GTK.
- Customization of applications to ease use on small screens by students.
- Kernel drivers test and packaging using DKMS.
- Create and maintain DEB packages.

• Hardware prototypes evaluation.

PressEnter Coop: Full stack developer

2012-2015

PressEnter was a cooperative custom software development firm. As a full stack developer there I built applications for various customers. I also took part in projects planning.

- Web applications development using Python and PHP5 (Django and Symfony2).
- Projects management.

Education Ministry (GCBA): PHP developer

2008-2012

Buenos Aires City Government (GCBA) Education Ministry is responsible for the education of 700.000 students in ~2300 schools. I was part of the team that developed web applications (using Symfony1) to ease management.

- Development web applications to manage students inscriptions, grades and teachers information.
- Development of the application that provides users unified login and security management.

Sociedad Hebraica Argentina: PHP developer

2004-2008

Sociedad Hebraica Argentina is a social club with around 8000 members. My job there was to create and maintain an ecosystem of applications for the club administration.

- Development of a custom PHP4 frameworks
- Design and develop accounting, invoicing, reports, members and suppliers physical access control and booking web applications
- Train new developers

Personal Projects

On my spare time I enjoy doing small projects and solving coding problems (https://www.hackerrank.com/miguel garcia ar) for learning and keeping up to date.

example-shop-py (https://github.com/miguelgarcia/example-shop-py): My goal was to try the latest versions of Flask, SQLAlchemy, Marshmallow, factoryboy, pytest, CircleCI and also create something simple

Marshmallow, factoryboy, pytest, CircleCl and also create something state that can be shown in my portfolio.

So, in this project I implemented a REST API to track products, customers and sells. The API provides CRUD functionality and statistics reports from custom SQLAlchemy queries.

neural-network-py (https://github.com/miguelgarcia/neural-

network-py): I wanted to learn the fundamentals of neural networks. After
investigating the mathematics and algorithms behind the "learning" I
implemented from scratch a configurable multilayer perceptron that can be
trained and executed. The code is 100% Python3 + Numpy.

I tested the multilayer perceptron implementing a handwritten digits recognizer for the MNIST data set, achieving a success rate of ~93%

IMBDB scraping (https://github.com/miguelgarcia/imdb scraping):

Extract movies and actors information from imdb.com to a Mongo database using Scrapy.

Skills List

This is a non - exhaustive list of my skills:

Python: Flask, Django, pytest, SQLAlchemy, Scrapy

Cloud: Kubernetes; AWS: EC2, Elastic Beanstalk, S3, RDS; Docker: compose,

custom images

JS: React, react-router, redux

PHP: Symfony3

Data bases: SQL, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB

Other: Scrum, C++, CI, Git, Linux programming, OpenCV, Apache, Nginx, Bonita

BPMS

Languages

Spanish: Native
English: Advanced